<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>NewPirateOfUASea's blog</title>
        <link>https://newpirateofuaseas.github.io/personal-page</link>
        <description>I write on tech and whatnot</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 21:42:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/nuxt-community/feed-module</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zoomer thoughts on RSS]]></title>
            <guid>https://newpirateofuaseas.github.io/personal-page/on-rss</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[My rant about RSS and a few words about TUI]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>On RSS</h1>

<p>RSS saves me so much time! I no longer spend time looking at recommendations on YouTube, etc., but only follow the people I really care about. Well, that&#39;s why i decided to use <a href="https://github.com/nuxt-community/feed-module">@nuxtjs/feed</a> in this project. </p>

<p>By the way, I use <a href="https://newsboat.org/">Newsboat</a>. <img alt="newsboat screenshot" src="https://newsboat.org/images/2.25-screenshot_1x-33f26153.png"/> The main reason i use TUI applications whenever it&#39;s possible, is because those app are keyboard-driven, which is much better for your wrist health </p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why I'm worried about future of vue.js]]></title>
            <guid>https://newpirateofuaseas.github.io/personal-page/on-vue-3</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[On future of vue.js]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Why I&#39;m worried about the future of Vue.js</h1>

<p>For those unaware - <a href="https://gist.github.com/tkrotoff/b1caa4c3a185629299ec234d2314e190">Vue.js is one of the 3 most popular javascript frameworks</a>. 
It would be a good place to start with why I care about this topic: I love using vue, it provides great DX for small teams, and it&#39;s my favorite JS framework. Having said that, let&#39;s dive right into the topic.</p>

<h2>Vue 3</h2>

<p>I&#39;ll start with the positives: Vue 3 removed <a href="https://v3.vuejs.org/guide/migration/filters.html">filters</a>, various sources also report that performance has been <a href="https://geckodynamics.com/blog/vue2-vs-vue3">drastically improved</a> referring to this <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VJFx-kQ4KjJmnpDXIEaig-cVAAJtpIGLZNbv3Lr4CR0/edit#gid=0">document</a>. I couldn&#39;t verify if this document is legit though. But I think DX has been greatly improved for sure, especially since Typescript compatibility has been improved.</p>

<h2>Drawbacks</h2>

<h3>Composition API</h3>

<p>While I don&#39;t have any problems with the composition API itself, I think this only complicates things. Unlike React which stated that they actually keep class components for backwards compatibility, but for new components you have to use hooks:</p>

<blockquote><blockquote><p><strong>Should I use Hooks, classes, or a mix of both?</strong>
When you’re ready, we’d encourage you to start trying Hooks in new components you write. Make sure everyone on your team is on board with using them and familiar with this documentation. We don’t recommend rewriting your existing classes to Hooks unless you planned to rewrite them anyway (e.g. to fix bugs).
Source: https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-faq.html</p></blockquote></blockquote>

<p>The Vue team goes the other way and claims that the Composition API is purely <em>additive</em>:</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>The composition API is additive</strong>, it’s a new feature, but it doesn’t and will not replace the good ole “Options API” you know and love from Vue 1 and 2. Just consider this new API as another tool in your toolbox that may come in handy in certain situations that feel a little clumsy to solve with the Options API. -- <a href="https://github.com/LinusBorg">Thorsten Lünborg</a>
Source: https://www.vuemastery.com/blog/vue-3-data-down-events-up/</p><p>I think Ari brings up an excellent point that when composition API just hasn&#39;t quite clicked like, “Why would I need that? The options API is working for me.” That&#39;s great. That means you don&#39;t need it. I think that&#39;s really important to emphasize here is that this is not something you need to go and rewrite your app in. It&#39;s a technique that when you have this problem that you need, just like in Damien’s button example, there&#39;s a reason why a component that&#39;s props heavy becomes very difficult to maintain, because now you basically have to read documentation to use it. Why slots becomes an incredible asset and tool to solve a problem of too many props. Similarly, the composition API is not like, drop the options do composition. <strong>It&#39;s an additive thing that when you have a problem that it can solve, it&#39;s really great for that.</strong> -- <a href="https://www.bencodezen.io/">Ben Hong</a>
Source: https://enjoythevue.io/episodes/48/</p><p>Without trying to argue, just out of interest: why Vue is is less dev happiness than Vue 2? Options API didn&#39;t change that much, and the <strong>Composition API is purely additive</strong>. Why do you find Vue 3 less enjoyable than version 2? --<a href="https://www.nataliatepluhina.com/">Natalia Tepluhina</a>
Source: https://twitter.com/N_Tepluhina/status/1349429774729572352</p></blockquote>

<p>This fact makes it unclear whether you should use Options API or Composition API in any given situation. This also means that you should be familiar with both APIs as they are accepted by popular libraries like <a href="https://vuelidate.js.org/">Vuelidate</a> or <a href="https://vuetifyjs.com/en/">Vuetify</a>. In other words, there is no such thing as an <em>additive</em> API.</p>

<h3>Typescript</h3>

<p>While it is really important to have strong types, especially in large projects, a structural type system is not enough today when web applications can be used in important things like <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/251225200_Web-Based_Applications_in_Healthcare">healthcare</a> (which, firstly, is a big mistake, but this is a completely different topic), and the chosen typing system can even be <a href="https://youtu.be/jnSHRPCTFPc?t=727">cause of death (RU)</a>. The problem is that Vue only officially supports typescript, and <a href="https://rescript-lang.org/">Rescript/BuckleScript</a> or <a href="https://hegel.js.org/">Hegel</a> isn&#39;t even an option. On the other hand, React, being simple in nature, is <a href="https://rescript-lang.org/docs/react/latest/introduction">easy to use with Rescript</a>.</p>

<h3>Mixins</h3>

<p>Fortunately or not, mixins are becoming less popular thanks to the Composition API. However, mixins are a real pain to work with. Don&#39;t believe me? Try to understand how this component works - https://github.com/bootstrap-vue/bootstrap-vue/blob/dev/src/components/carousel/carousel.js </p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>